hikarabita kotoba wo tsunai de
connecting old words that have been used up
soredemo bokura shinpuru na omoi wo tsutaetai dake na no
I just want to convey my simple thoughts
fukinukeru kusunda ano hi no kaze wa
that day's faint wind blows away
kinou no haikyo ni uchi sutete
at the castle ruins of yesterday
kimi to warau ima wo ikiru no da
I'll laugh with you and live for the moment
soredemo ano dekigoto ga kimi wo kurushimeru daro
still that incident will continue to trouble you, right?
dakarakoso sayonara nanda
that's why it must be good-bye
konomama nanimo nokorazu ni anata to wakachiau dake
leaving nothing behind, let us share what is left
yagate bokura wa sore ga subetee dato kigatsuite
in time, we'll realize that it was everything
kanashimi wa hoo wo tsutatte namida no kawa ni naru dake
and sadness will touch our cheeks, creating a river of tears
yureru omoi wa tsuyoi uzu ni natte tokeau no yo
Trembling thoughts swept into a vortex and melting away
Okay! Drink! Sing!
Let's have fun!
Good grief... This is too much for...
a pre-celebration.
Did you take care of the business?
Yes...
More importantly
the rain's starting to let up.
Shouldn't you quickly put an end
to this farce of a race?
Fine.
Guess I'll go for a run!
A-Above here huh?
Yeah...
It's a quite a long staircase.
They're also called
the Stone Steps that Tear Hearts Apart.
Heh, cool!
Let's go at a sprint!
Hey, he's kidding right?
What kind of stamina does he have?
Boss.
It seems Idate is heading this way!
He hasn't run away
just like you said Boss.
Of course...
I saw potential in him.
Now it's just a little more!
Run Idate!
Just Before
the Goal!
The Fierce Battle
of Roaring Thunder
Hey... you...!
Huh?
Let me tell you...
It's not like I trust you
or anything yet okay?
Yeah yeah whatever.
It doesn't really matter to me.
There's a person
who still trusts you right?!
During the Chunin Exam...
Huh?
You said that a tenth problem
appeared, right?
Yeah. It was a weird problem to determine
whether you'd take the problem or not.
Three years ago...
I got a similar problem...
Okay, now I'm going to
give the tenth problem.
The tenth problem...
What kind of problem is
Big Brother going to give?!
The tenth problem is a battle
with the Three-Man Squad
you were teamed up with.
The three of you will compete against
each other this exercise.
And among you...
one of you will be failed!
And the one who is failed
will remain a Genin for life
and we will never again
let them take the Chunin Exam!
N-No way...
Then for what purpose
were we together until now?
I make the rules here.
Back-talk is not allowed at all!
If you want to withdraw
you should do so.
Withdrawing here and
waiting half a year is also a way.
If one person among
the three withdraws
of course all three members
will be disqualified.
But you will be allowed
to take the Chunin Exam
one more time in half a year.
So what will you do?
One comrade will be dropped.
I have the confidence to pass.
But one of them will remain
a Genin for life.
It's a choice between
comrades and your life.
If you're going to quit
now's the time.
Is there nobody else
who's going to withdraw?
We're good then.
Okay to everyone who
has remained here...
I render you disqualified!
Wh-Why...?
H-Hold on a minute!
I prepared myself and remained here!
Such preparedness is below contempt!
Scums like you don't have
the qualifications to become Chunin!
That's all!
I see...
What kind of a test was it
for you guys?
I forgot...
I mean it was explained to me
but I didn't really get it.
Trusting in my big brother's words
I remained in the classroom.
And yet I was failed!
No way could I take that.
I questioned my big brother.
Big Brother!
What's up with that test?!
A Shinobi reads the double bluff.
You should've understood
that was the test.
Even so I can't accept that!
No matter how dangerous
isn't it necessary to have
the courage to plunge into any mission?!
Idate.
Can you really not accept it?
Of course not such a...
You... quit as a Ninja.
If you're telling me to quit
then I will.
But tell me why I'm no good!
That's something you should
realize yourself
with your own power.
To this day... I don't understand
the answer to that.
So after that
you were deceived by Aoi, huh?
Yeah, that's right.
We made it... to the top!
I'm going by myself from here.
You rest!
Huh?! You still saying stuff like that?!
I can't be asking you guys
to help any more.
There's no point if I don't win by myself
on my own strength!
Oh... hey! Idate!
I can make it! It seems
Sakura's special medicine has worked!
Blast!
This doesn't hurt!
I'm back in the game...
from here!
If we cross this suspension bridge
it's Ouzu Island, huh?
We should hurry.
It seems Idate has made it
to the Modoroki Shrine.
What?!
It seems we underestimated
the Leaf Genin a bit...
You jerk!
You didn't finish them?!
Now's not the time to be talking
about stuff like that.
Please cross the bridge quickly!
Useless Ninja!
Hey! I'm only helping you
because it's the job.
I'll waste you if you keep
talking smart to me.
I-I'm sorry...
If you've understood
then get a move on!
Y-Yes!
There he is! That Fukusuke jerk!
This is quite something.
I never thought
you'd make it this far.
That's the...
Blade of the Thunder God!
Stop!
Stop kicking a dead horse.
Nobody is a match for
the legendary Blade of the Thunder God
said to have been used
by the Second Hokage.
You should know this well.
After all you're the man
who stole this for me.
Blast...
Mud balls, huh?
It's just like a kid's fight.
Sorry, I didn't have
any Kunai Knives.
Naruto...
But you won't be able to dodge
the next ball just with that.
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
He's concentrating
the Chakra in his palm.
Here I come!
Once more!
I don't know what
you intend to do but...
Ninja Art: Senbon Rainstorm!
Too bad.
This Blade of the Thunder God
cuts through anything!
Even Chakra itself is no exception.
Naruto!
I have to make doubly sure
so that nothing troublesome
will happen again.
I'm your opponent!
Keep your hands off Idate!
Humph, are you still
saying such things?
Saving each other protecting each other
trusting each other.
It ticks me off!
The weak can't survive
if they don't support each other.
So they trust people easily
and are betrayed.
Weaklings like you guys
should just run about and away.
Right, Idate?
It was like that also
when you stole
this Blade of the Thunder God, right?
I can see it.
That's the Village Hidden in the Rain.
Aoi-sensei?!
Aoi-sensei!
Idate...
B-Big Brother...
You idiot!
Go back to the village immediately
and surrender yourself!
You?!
Do you know what
you have done?
What?!
Strict as always, eh?
And he's your cute little brother.
But it's truly perfect that
you've shown up here.
Aoi-sensei...
This forbidden Jutsu scroll
can't be deciphered
unless you're Jonin class.
I'll have the brothers
betray the Leaf Village together.
Ibiki, please decipher it already.
I refuse.
So are you choosing death
together with Idate?
Such as he is
he's also a Shinobi.
He's not afraid of death.
It doesn't seem so.
This face is one taut with fear.
I'm quitting as a Ninja!
So please don't kill me!
Please decipher it.
You don't want to see
your cute little brother killed
before your eyes do you?
Little brother you say?
That fool?
Big Brother...
Such a threat means nothing to me.
Hey, Ibiki, is the Village Hidden
in the Leaves that important?
Even if you protect it at
the risk of your own life
you're nothing but a pawn!
So that's why
you became a traitor?
You're a pathetic man!
You punk!
Idate!
You run away!
What about you Big Brother?
I'll go after I clean up
the mess here!
I don't think so!
Big Brother!
Go quickly!
But Big Brother...!
Go! Having you stay is a burden!
I won't let you!
Go!
So appalling...
that he'd risk
his life for such an idiotic guy.
All you could do after that
was run.
You could've returned
to the village and called for help.
But you didn't do that.
Thinking Ibiki was dead
was no excuse!
The fact is he was alive...
In that regard,
Ibiki was admirable.
Not only did he completely endure
repeated interrogation
but he also retrieved
the Forbidden Jutsu scroll...
without having confessed to anything!
And to think that he did
all this
for his good-for-nothing little brother.
You betrayed your village,
abandoned your older brother
and came to think of only yourself.
Even Ibiki who is blood-related
and risked his life to save you
you didn't trust him!
Afraid of being accused
you didn't trust the Village Hidden
in the Leaves your birthplace...
You trust nobody.
You're not trusted by anyone.
For me, there is no pupil
as excellent as you.
As a reward,
I'll let you die in one instant.
Idate!
Sasuke... Sakura!
Rest Naruto!
I'll beat this guy!
Don't be acting cool.
You can't beat me no matter
how many people show up.
Me, Aoi Rokusho
the Rain Jonin who possesses
the Blade of the Thunder God.
Is that so?
Interesting.
The Blade of the Thunder God
and my Chidori!
Let's test which is better!
The rumors were true.
The survivor of the village's honourable
Uchiha Clan...
is just a good-for-nothing kid...
Sasuke!
Run, Sakura!
He'll show no mercy
no matter who the person is.
Everyone will be killed!
No way!
Huh?!
We'll protect you
no matter what.
We promised that didn't we?!
Trust us!
Now all that's left is
the wounded rabbit
and the excellent pupil huh?
You two together
go to the next world.
Take it back!
What're you talking about?
What you said...
earlier!
Don't mess...
with the Uchiha...
with me!
Why you...!
Sasuke!
Sasuke! Get up!
How very cold the bottom
of the ocean must be.
Stop!
Idate!
Sakura!
GET UP aa sumimasen
get up! oh, I'm sorry
goku tama ni boku tama ni
once in a long while, once in a while
yume ni yabureru hito no kakera ga
the remnants of a person broken by dreams
yama no you ni mieru
Iook like a mountain
kamisama ni hotokesama ni
clinging to God, clinging to Buddha
sugari naiteru hito no kakera ga
the remnants of a person crying
yama no you ni mieru
Iook like a mountain
danran dansu de RANDEBUU
rendezvous with a happy dance circle
ore shouri no poozu da randaran
this is my victory pose, round and around
SHEIKU SHEIKU SHEIKU sagasou janai
shake shake shake let's look
owaranai baibai no RIZUMU de
with a bye-bye rhythm that never ends
yama no you ni mieru
Iook like a mountain
What the heck should we do?
That sword of the Second Hokage
won't budge an inch
even with Sasuke's Chidori
or my Rasengan!
But I can't lose this battle.
I won't run away no matter what!
If my techniques aren't going to work
I'll just have to keep trying!
Next time:
"You Can Reach It, Idate! The Last Spring of Determination!!"